{"1": {"question": "Mozart: What period is the initial development of chamber music linked to?", "correct": "Classical Period", "incorrect": ["Baroque Period", "Romantic Period", "Jazz Period", "The 80's"]}, "2": {"question": "Mozart: What feature separates the string quartet from Baroque forms?", "correct": "Basso continuo", "incorrect": ["It requires a violin", "Its music is better", "Cheaper", "Its instrumentation is different"]}, "3": {"question": "Mozart: When did the first string quartets appear?", "correct": "In the 1760's", "incorrect": ["Stone Age", "In the 1800's", "In the 1780's", "Jesus time, brah"]}, "4": {"question": "Mozart: Where did the first string quartets appear?", "correct": "South Germany, Austria, Bohemia", "incorrect": ["In ur mum's basement", "China", "Germany and Bolivia", "New Orleans"]}, "5": {"question": "Mozart: To which socioeconomic group did this music appeal?", "correct": "Enlightened' upper classes", "incorrect": ["Poor lower classes", "Hard-working American taxpayers", "Poor upper classes", "Rich homeless people"]}, "6": {"question": "Mozart: How many players are required and what kind of space is it played in?", "correct": "4 players in a small space", "incorrect": ["4 players in a large space", "3 players in a small space", "5 players in a large space", "The entire population of the Asian continent (approximately 4.5 billion)"]}, "7": {"question": "Mozart: Where were the quartets composed and when?", "correct": "In Vienna, between 1782 and 1785", "incorrect": ["In ur mum's basement", "In Italy between 1782 and 1785", "Nazi Germany", "Germany in the early 1800's"]}, "8": {"question": "Mozart: How many of the quartets were composed?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["5", "1", "4", "1,000,000,000,000"]}, "9": {"question": "Mozart: Who were the set of quartets dedicated to?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Bach", "Mozart", "Beethoven", "Jesus"]}, "10": {"question": "Mozart: To which work(s) were the works written in response to?", "correct": "Haydn's Op. 33 set", "incorrect": ["Mozart's Op. 10 set", "Beethoven's Op. 28 set", "Haydn's Op. 34 set", "Baby shark"]}, "11": {"question": "Mozart: What are the four movements in this String quartet K 387?", "correct": "Fast movement, Slow movement, Minuet and trio, Fast finale", "incorrect": ["Fast movement, even faster movement, even more faster movement, a movement that's so fast you didn't even realise it was playing until it ended", "Fast movement, Slow movement, Fast movement, Slow movement", "Fast movement, fast movement, slow movement, minuet and trio", "Slow movement, slower movment, fast finale, minuet and trio"]}, "12": {"question": "Mozart: What are the two main archetypes of a theme in the Classical style?", "correct": "Sentence and period", "incorrect": ["Sentence and full stop", "Sentence and response", "Dark mode and light mode", "Syncopation", "Archetypes don't exist, conspiracy confirmed"]}, "13": {"question": "Mozart: What comprises a 'sentence' theme?", "correct": "A 'presentation' phrase then a 'continuation and cadential' phrase", "incorrect": ["A theme that sentences.", "A continuation phrase then a presentation of the results", "A basic idea then a repetition of the basic ideas", "Some words and then a full stop at the end."]}, "14": {"question": "Mozart: What does a presentation phrase comprise of?", "correct": "A two bar basic idea which is either repeated or modified", "incorrect": ["An eight bar basic idea thats repeated again so its 16 so thats quick maths", "A two bar idea followed by another two bar idea", "A four bar idea which is repeated", "A song thats topping the charts"]}, "15": {"question": "Mozart: How many parts does the development have?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["3", "5", "6", "As many as there are points in my IQ (in that case, none)"]}, "16": {"question": "Mozart: What type of theme does the first four bars of the exposition suggest?", "correct": "Period-type theme", "incorrect": ["Sentence theme", "Yellow theme", "Halloween theme", "Cadential theme"]}, "17": {"question": "Mozart: Instead of returning to the initial basic idea at bars 5 and 6, what does the melody do?", "correct": "Fragmentary process like the 'continuation' of the sentence type", "incorrect": ["A process called photosynthesis", "The melody exposes the material from the development", "It finishes in an imperfect cadence", "It votes for Biden"]}, "18": {"question": "Mozart: What kind of theme does this become?", "correct": "A kind of 'hybrid' theme of the period and sentence themes", "incorrect": ["A triple theme", "A period theme", "A sentence theme", "It doesn't"]}, "19": {"question": "Mozart: How many additional bars are added to the standard eight-bar structure at bar 1?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "8", "1", "262"]}, "20": {"question": "Mozart: What are the two cadences that occur at bar 8 and bar 10?", "correct": "Interrupted and Perfect", "incorrect": ["Interrupted and Plagal ", "Plagal and Perfect ", "Pianist", "Imperfect and Perfect"]}, "21": {"question": "Mozart: In which bar does the transition begin?", "correct": "Bar 11", "incorrect": ["Bar 18", "Bar 1", "Bar 9", "Bar Mitzvah"]}, "22": {"question": "Mozart: In which parts is the basic idea restated then imitated?", "correct": "Second violin then first violin", "incorrect": ["First violin then second violin", "Second violin then third violin", "First violin then the baritone saxophone", "Upper North Shore"]}, "23": {"question": "Mozart: To where does the piece modulate to by bar 16?", "correct": "Dominant", "incorrect": ["Subdominant", "Tonic", "Leading Note", "Alabama"]}, "24": {"question": "Mozart: Which key is bars 21-24 in, and what does this create?", "correct": "D major, creating a drawn-out imperfect cadence in dominant key", "incorrect": ["G major, creating a perfect cadence", "F flat major, creating disharmony amongst the music community", "E major, creating contrast to the previous section", "It is in the key of C chromatic scale because that is what everything is in (massive brain moment)"]}, "25": {"question": "Mozart: What does Mozart play tricks on?", "correct": "Expectations of Classical thematic conventions", "incorrect": ["His unicycle", "His own mind, he was delusional", "Expectations of Jazz people", "Everyone and everything and everyone"]}, "26": {"question": "Mozart: How many extra bars are added to the standard eight-bar structure commencing at bar 25?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["4", "2", "1", "26"]}, "27": {"question": "Mozart: What does the repitition of the basic idea a step lower from bar 25 at bar 27 suggest?", "correct": "A sentence-type theme", "incorrect": ["A period theme", "Mozart was loony ", "It doesn't suggest anything, stop being so suspicious", "The basic idea was repeated a step lower"]}, "28": {"question": "Mozart: At bar 29, what would usually follow the repition of the basic idea?", "correct": "Fragmentation and continuation", "incorrect": ["Repitition", "Syncopation", "The basic idea", "Sentence and period"]}, "29": {"question": "Mozart: What happens at bar 29 instead?", "correct": "A two bar contrasting idea with a weak imperfect cadence", "incorrect": ["A similar idea with a perfect cadence", "A contrasting idea with an imperfect cadence", "The basic idea followed by a plagal cadence", "The basic idea is repeated in a different key"]}, "30": {"question": "Mozart: Which bars are the first and second subordinate themes?", "correct": "First is 25, second is 39", "incorrect": ["First is 39, second is 49", "They happen simultaneously", "First is at bar 40, second at 50", "Yellow submarine"]}, "31": {"question": "Mozart: What is the name of the totality of subordinate themes?", "correct": "Subordinate theme group", "incorrect": ["Subordinate themes", "Ordinate Subtheme group", "Total of subordinate themes", "It is themes of subdorndasdlfk"]}, "32": {"question": "Mozart: How does the second subordinate theme differr from the first subordinate theme?", "correct": "It is less distinctive, consisting of more 'generic' passage work", "incorrect": ["It is more distinctive, as it includes the original material while experimenting with it", "It stays quite similar", "It comes after the first subordinate theme", "It is less distinctive, consisting of very repetitve phrases"]}, "33": {"question": "Mozart: Nearing the end of the exposition, there is a reptitive harmonic motion, mainly through which chords?", "correct": "IV-V-I", "incorrect": ["I-V-vi", "V-VI-I", "I-IV-V", "ii-V-I"]}, "34": {"question": "Mozart: What kind of cadence occurs at bar 47?", "correct": "Interrupted", "incorrect": ["Plagal", "Imperfect", "Perfect", "Cadence constructions"]}, "35": {"question": "Mozart: What closes the second subordinate theme and where?", "correct": "A harmonic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 49", "incorrect": ["A harmonic progression towards an imperfect cadence at bar 49", "A chromatic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 39", "A ii-V-I progression at bar 49", "A harmonic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 49"]}, "36": {"question": "Mozart: How many bars at the end of the exposition are included in the 'closing section'?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["All of them", "8", "4", "2"]}, "37": {"question": "Mozart: What usually comprises a closing sections?", "correct": "A series of cadence-like gestures (codettas)", "incorrect": ["Notes", "References to the basic idea from the opening", "A series of perfect cadences", "Dramatic phrasing"]}, "38": {"question": "Mozart: What is presented in the case of this closing section at the end of the exposition?", "correct": "Cadence-like gestures (marked by a and b)", "incorrect": ["Notes", "Chords from the development section", "Nothing (ladies and gentlemen, introducing - drum roll please - Mozart the rebel)", "Conclusive phrasing"]}, "39": {"question": "Mozart: Who is Joe?", "correct": "Joe mama", "incorrect": ["Joe Biden", "Joseph Stalin", "Joe's sandwich bar", "Joe (musician)"]}, "40": {"question": "Mozart: Where is the logical place to close the exposition?", "correct": "Bar 53", "incorrect": ["Bar 50", "Bar 55", "When the exposition starts because nobody wants to listen to it", "China"]}, "41": {"question": "Mozart: What is presented at bar 53 in the case of this piece?", "correct": "Also a cadential formula, but something entirely new and distinctive", "incorrect": ["Not a cadential formula, something entirely new and distinctive", "A cadential formula, with a closing perfect cadence that is completely to be expected", "A cadential progression that happens at the end of every exposition", "Global warming"]}, "42": {"question": "Mozart: What makes bars 54 and 55 distinctive?", "correct": "Dotted rhythms and total homophony", "incorrect": ["It is so polyphonic that you decide to become breatharian", "The articulative phrasing", "The notes don't fit the chords"]}, "43": {"question": "Mozart: What bar does the development start?", "correct": "56", "incorrect": ["65", "70", "1", "62"]}, "44": {"question": "Mozart: Part 1 of the development contains how many phrases?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["2", "4", "8", "17"]}, "45": {"question": "Mozart: What is the structure of each phrase in part 1 of the development?", "correct": "Motif x followed by a newly composed extension", "incorrect": ["Motif x followed by motif y", "Complete random structure where nobody has any idea what is happening", "A motif that is repeated", "Motif a followed by motif b followed by motif c followed by motif d etc."]}, "46": {"question": "Mozart: The first phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "1st Violin", "incorrect": ["Viola", "Cello", "Saxophone", "2nd Violin"]}, "47": {"question": "Mozart: The second phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "2nd Violin", "incorrect": ["Viola", "Cello", "Saxophone", "1st Violin"]}, "48": {"question": "Mozart: The third phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "Viola", "incorrect": ["1st Violin", "2nd Violin", "3rd Violin", "Cello"]}, "49": {"question": "Mozart: Could Mozart shred", "correct": "Probably not", "incorrect": ["Absolutely", "Without a doubt", "Definitely", "Mhm"]}, "50": {"question": "Mozart: What key is the development mainly in?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["A major", "G major", "D minor ", "Circular Quay"]}, "51": {"question": "Mozart: The first phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Commences in D major and concludes in E minor", "incorrect": ["Stays in D major", "Cycle of fifths progression towards C major", "Commences in D major and ends in A major", "Provides an opportunity for a bass solo"]}, "52": {"question": "Mozart: The second phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Moves through a circle of fifths progression toward C major", "incorrect": ["Remains in C major", "Commences in D major then moves to E minor", "Nothing, everyone just goes quiet and stares at the floor", "It searches for resolution in the tonic"]}, "53": {"question": "Mozart: The third phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Remains in C major", "incorrect": ["Remains in D major", "Commences in C major then moves to A minor", "Cycle of fifths progression towards the tonic, D major", "Moves to the dominant key, A major"]}, "54": {"question": "Mozart: How can the harmonic nature of the music be described at the first part of the devleopment section?", "correct": "Flexible", "incorrect": ["Consistent", "Boring", "Unpredictable", "Repetitive"]}, "55": {"question": "Mozart: What does the viola complete its thematic entry (motif + extension) with in phrase 3 of part 1 of the development?", "correct": "An unaccompanied flourish, which is a further extension", "incorrect": ["A phrase that fits a perfect cadence", "A phrase that fits an imperfect cadence", "Fragments of the basic idea", "A dessert"]}, "56": {"question": "Mozart: The viola's solo passage in the third phrase of part 1 of the development creates a model that is used where?", "correct": "The sequence for the commencement of part 2 of the devleopment", "incorrect": ["The sequence for the end of part 1 of the development", "At the end of part 2 of the development", "At the end of the development", "In a showroom"]}, "57": {"question": "Mozart: Where and what size is the model created by the viola's solo passage in the third phrase of part 1 of the development?", "correct": "A two bar unit in bars 72-73, heard another three times in sequence", "incorrect": ["A two bar unit in bars 70-71, heard another three times in sequence", "A four bar unit in bars 72-75, heard again in sequence", "A four bar unit in bars 70-73, heard another three times in sequence", "A 2 minute long model that outlines the points that the team will debate"]}, "58": {"question": "Mozart: The sequence that the viola's model in the third phrase of part 1 of the development is  played over what?", "correct": "Unresolved dominant 7th chords on a chromatically rising bass line", "incorrect": ["A harmonic progression of ii-V-I that continues with a bass line", "Unresolved diminished 7th chords on a chromatically rising bass line", "Imperfect and interrupted cadences ", "The double bass parts"]}, "59": {"question": "Mozart: How does the second part of the development constrast to the first?", "correct": "The second establishes a sense of purpose in constrast to the more exploratory and hesitant first part", "incorrect": ["The second part is in a different mode as opposed to the first one", "The second part is more hesitant as opposed to the first which has a sense of purpose", "More expressive techniques are used as opposed to the first part which lacks interest and variety", "It doesn't happen"]}, "60": {"question": "Mozart: What is often thought of as the core of the development?", "correct": "The moment of decisiveness (sequencing techniques following a less clearly directed part)", "incorrect": ["The new theme being introduced", "A hard seed, similar to a peach", "The basic idea from the exposition being developed", "The movement into a different key that is not the dominant"]}, "61": {"question": "Mozart: At which bar does the sequencing finish in part 2 of the development?", "correct": "Bar 80", "incorrect": ["Bar 82", "Bar 78", "Bar 1", "Bar 92.5"]}, "62": {"question": "Mozart: What key does the sequencing in part 2 of the development finish in and the development remain in?", "correct": "E minor", "incorrect": ["G major", "C major", "A minor", "H diminished"]}, "63": {"question": "Mozart: Which bars in part 2 of the development confirm the key and dissipate the syncopation?", "correct": "80-81", "incorrect": ["81-82", "82-83", "1-170", "80-83"]}, "64": {"question": "Mozart: What begins at bar 82?", "correct": "A new thematic unit", "incorrect": ["A new era for the American people", "The closing section of the exposition", "A new motif ", "The development"]}, "65": {"question": "Mozart: What does the second thematic unit of part 2 of the development comprise?", "correct": "A two bar unit", "incorrect": ["A four bar unit", "An eight bar unit", "A sixteen bar unit", "A one bar unit"]}, "66": {"question": "Mozart: In which part does the second two bar unit in part 2 of the development occur and how many times?", "correct": "First violin twice", "incorrect": ["Second violin once", "Second violin twice", "First violin once", "Viola twice"]}, "67": {"question": "Mozart: From where do bars 86-89 draw material?", "correct": "Closing section of the exposition, in particular motifs b and c ", "incorrect": ["The beginning of the development section", "The beginning of the exposition, especially motif a", "One of Mozart's other works", "From a quarry"]}, "68": {"question": "Mozart: What does part 3 of the development commence with?", "correct": "A new sequence with a one bar model ", "incorrect": ["A new sequence with a two bar model", "A bang", "Material from the closing section of the exposition", "A sense of purpose"]}, "69": {"question": "Mozart: In what bar does part 3 of the development begin?", "correct": "Bar 90", "incorrect": ["Bar 82", "Bar 88", "Bar 102", "Bar 92"]}, "70": {"question": "Mozart: By how much higher is each sequence than the model at the beginning of part 3 of the developement?", "correct": "A perfect fourth", "incorrect": ["A perfect fifth", "An octave", "A tone", "Out of the audible spectrum"]}, "71": {"question": "Mozart: The first two sequences in part 3 of the development express what cadence type?", "correct": "V7-I", "incorrect": ["IV-I", "I-V7", "vi-vii", "All of the above"]}, "72": {"question": "Mozart: What happens at bars 92-93 instead of the expected V7-I?", "correct": "V7-VI", "incorrect": ["Viola", "V7-I", "I-V7", "Vi7-vi"]}, "73": {"question": "Mozart: What key does the new theme in part 3 of the development work towards (at bars 93-97)?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["A major", "B minor ", "C major", "All of the above"]}, "74": {"question": "Mozart: The exposition's closing section is heard again at bars 97-100, but it is in which key?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["D minor", "A major", "B minor", "E major"]}, "75": {"question": "Mozart: What is part 4 of the development usually called?", "correct": "Retransition", "incorrect": ["Transition", "Closing section ", "End bit", "The end of an old life but the beginning of a new one"]}, "76": {"question": "Mozart: What happens in part 4 of the development harmonically?", "correct": "The dominant harmony in the tonic key is introduced", "incorrect": ["The subordinate melody in the tonic key is introduced", "The subordinate themes are repeated in the harmonic parts", "The dominant harmony in the dominant key is introduced", "It has a solo"]}, "77": {"question": "Mozart: What two kinds of variation to the exposition can be expected in the recapitulation?", "correct": "Decorative and Structural", "incorrect": ["Structural and Exploratory", "Decorative and Festive", "Notational and Structural", "All of the above"]}, "78": {"question": "Mozart: What are decorative changes?", "correct": "Variations to expression; no material change", "incorrect": ["Variations to material; no expressional change", "Setting up a Christmas tree", "Any substantially new or altered material", "Ornamentations and trills added for interest"]}, "79": {"question": "Mozart: What are structural changes?", "correct": "Any substantially new or altered material", "incorrect": ["Changes to the layout of the section", "Different ideas replacing the old ones", "Variations to expression; no material change", "Like when a banana is genetically edited to become a pineapple"]}, "80": {"question": "Mozart: The plan of the recapitulation is fairly similar to the plan of the exposition, except for what key difference?", "correct": "Everything is now in the tonic", "incorrect": ["Everything is now in the dominant", "Everything is now in a minor key", "The structure of them are completely different", "Its at the end instead of the beginning"]}, "81": {"question": "Mozart: What and where is the only difference in the main theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "At bar 116, additional one-bar unit presented", "incorrect": ["At bar 118, additional one-bar unit presented", "At bar 116, additional two-bar unit presented", "At bar 120, additional four-bar unit presented", "There is no difference"]}, "82": {"question": "Mozart: What is the main alteration in the transition of the recapitulation?", "correct": "A structural change at bar 123, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "incorrect": ["A decorative change at bar 123, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "yeetus to the foetus", "A structural change at bar 125, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "The key is changed, meaning that the listener is thrown off"]}, "83": {"question": "Mozart: Are there any surprises in the first subordinate theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "No", "incorrect": ["Yes", "Maybe", "None of the above because there is no such thing as a subordinate theme", "Definitely possible but no because everything is not possibly definite"]}, "84": {"question": "Mozart: Are there any surprises in the second subordinate theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "None of the above because there is no such thing as a subordinate theme", "Definitely possible but possibly maybe because everything is not possibly definite"]}, "85": {"question": "Mozart: Does the closing section of the recapitulation differ from the closing section of the exposition and how?", "correct": "Yes, with some changes to octave reiger and two additional repeats of motive b", "incorrect": ["Yes, with some changes to the key and notation", "No it doesn't", "Yes, it contains different melodic ideas", "What's a closing section"]}}